Hanyuan Xiao

https://corneliushsiao.github.io/index.html

Introduction

I am a PhD student in Vision and Graphics Lab at Institute for Creative Technologies (ICT), an affiliated institution of University of Southern California. My research area is in neural rendering and human body performance capture.

EDUCATION

University of Southern California (USC)

Doctorate (PhD) in Computer Science; GPA: 3.87

Los Angeles, CA

Email: hanyuanx@usc.edu

Mobile: (518)407-9398

May 2024

University of Southern California (USC)

Los Angeles, CA

Master of Science (M.S.) in Data Science; GPA: 3.87

May 2021

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (RPI)

Troy, NY

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Science and Electrical Engineering (dual major); GPA: 3.95

May 2019

o Honor: Dean's Honor List (2015-2018), Distinguished Student

PATENT & PUBLICATIONS

Light Sampling Field and BRDF Representation for Physically-Based Neural Rendering

ICLR 2023 Poster

Multiview Neural Human Prediction Using Implicit Differentiable Renderer For Facial Expression, Body

• Pose Shape And Clothes Performance Capture

US 2022/0319055 A1

Systems and Methods for Physically-based Neural Face Shader via Volumetric Lightmaps

U.S. Provisional Application Serial No. 63/183,497

RELATED RESEARCH & PROJECTS

•	Authoring Material for Physically-based Neural Rendering
	Research project

Los Angeles, CA

 $May\ 2023$

May 2023

o Status: Submitted to Siggraph Asia'23

Free-View Volumetric Human Body Capture via Sparse Representation

Los Angeles, CA

Research project

• Status: Submitted to ICCV'23

MVS-PERF: Multiview SMPL-X and Clothes Performance Capture using NeRF

Los Angeles, CA

Internship project

May 2021 — December 2021

FaceReal: Physically-based Neural Face Shader via Volumetric Lightmaps

Los Angeles, CA

Research project

Research project

October 2020 — May 2022

One-shot Aerial: 3D Scene Segmentation and Reconstruction from Aerial Viewpoint

Los Angeles, CA

May 2020 — October 2020

3D Reconstruction of Rigid Objects by Correspondence

Los Angeles, CA

Research project
Food Method GAN

September 2019 — March 2020

Course project

Los Angeles, CA September 2019 — December 2019

Water Freezing Simulation

Los Angeles, CA

• Course project

November 2019 — December 2019

VR Acquisition & Application Development for School of Engineering Research

Troy, NY

Undergraduate Researcher

 $January\ 2018\ --\ Spring\ 2019$

Related Courseworks

• Differential Geometry	2023 Spring
• Advanced Computer Vision	2020 Fall
• Deep Learning and its Applications	2019 Fall
• 3-D Graphics and Rendering	2019 Fall
Machine Learning From Data	2018 Fall
• Digital Signal Processing	2018 Fall

SKILLS

• Programming Languages: Python, C++, C, Matlab, LaTeX

• Software: Blender (BPY), Autodesk Maya, PyTorch, Tensorflow, SteamVR, MS Office, AutoCAD

• Hardware: Arduino, PSpice

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

Introduction to Artificial Intelligence

Los Angeles, CA

January 2022 — May 2023

Teaching Assistant Los Angeles, CA

Discrete Methods in Computer Science September 2022 — December 2022

Research Intern San Jose, CA

Sony R&D Center May 2021 — December 2021

Mentor: Qing Zhang Manager: Kenji Tashiro

o **Topic**: Multi-view Neural Human Performance Capture

Teaching Assistant

Data Structures and Object Oriented Design

Los Angeles, CA

January 2021 — December 2021

Teaching Assistant Troy, NY

Laboratory Introduction to Embedded Control

September 2016 — May 2019

Languages

Chinese (Mandarin)

5 - Native fluency

English

5 - Bilingual fluency